Charles Green Shaw
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Writings, 1910-1971, Series 3:; (Boxes 3-20, 46; 17.5 linear ft.)
  - Writings by Shaw, 1910-1971, 3.1:
    - Fiction, circa 1920s-circa 1970, 3.1.2:
      - "The Two Gardenias," undated (Box 13)
      - "What a Bore," undated (Box 13)
      - "The Wonderful See-All Machine," undated (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, 1910-circa 1970, 3.1.3:
      Speeches include a salutatory to the Berkeley-Columbia Class of 1910; an untitled talk on illustration read before the American Women's Association, 1941; and an undated talk about Shaw's book, "Heart in a Hurricane."
      - Fragments, undated (Box 13)
      - Lyrics, by Shaw and Others, undated (Box 13)
      - Speeches,1910, 1941, undated (Box 13)
    - Non-Fiction, circa 1920s-circa 1970, 3.1.4:
      - "All Round the Town," undated (Box 13)
      - "American As Spoken," undated (Box 13)
      - "An Animal ABC," undated, (illustrated) (Box 13)
      - "Apothecary Shop – 1926 Model," 1925 (Box 13)
      - "At the Tea-Room Restaurant," undated (Box 13)
      - "By the Sad Sea Waves," undated (Box 13)
      - "The Christmas Guess Book," undated, (illustrated) (Box 13)
      - "Credo," undated (Box 13)
      - "Cupid's Practical Dictionary," undated (Box 13)
      - "The Dance Hall," undated (Box 13)
      - "Delicatessen," undated (Box 13)
      - "The Dim Nineties," undated (Box 13)
      - "The First Days of Clubdom," undated (Box 13)
      - "Food For Thought: A Glance into Certain of the World's Distinguished Mess Halls," undated (Box 13)
      - "The Guess-What-I-Am Book," undated, (illustrated) (Box 13)
      - "Heart Failure," 1929 (Box 13)
      - "How I Feel about Love and the Rest of It," undated (Box 13)
      - "How I Feel about Chow Emporiums," undated (Box 13)
      - "How I Feel about Things Now (After a Good Many Years of Thinking it Over)," undated (Box 13)
      - "How I Learned What I Know About Women," undated (Box 13)
      - "How the Past Told the Future," undated (Box 13)
      - "I Knew the Town," undated (Box 13)
      - "The Important Book," undated, (2 folders; illustrated; see also: Box 46) (Box 13)
      - "In the Matter of Thing Amorous," undated (Box 13)
      - "Lady of Fashion – 1926 Model," 1926 (Box 13)
      - "The Little Mouse," undated, (illustrated) (Box 13)
      - "The Lobbyist," undated (Box 13)
      - "Lois Moran," undated (Box 13)
      - "London – Oddly Enough," undated (Box 13)
        (5 folders; includes incomplete text and addenda, photograph illustrations and captions, "eliminations" and notes)
      - "The Lover's Lexicon," undated (Box 14)
      - "Love's Lexicon," undated (Box 14)
      - "McSwibbs," undated (Box 14)
      - "A Metropolitan Antique" (Boston; with illustrations), undated (Box 14)
      - "A Metropolitan Antique" (New York; with illustrations), undated (Box 14)
      - "New York – Oddly Enough," circa 1938 (Box 14)
        (8 folders; includes 2 versions of incomplete text with many photograph illustrations removed)
      - "Odd Nooks of Modern New York," undated, (2 folders) (Box 14)
      - "An Old American Custom," undated (Box 14)
      - "Old Mother Booze" (illustrated), undated (Box 14)
      - "Paris – Oddly Enough," undated (Box 14)
        (4 folders; includes text with photograph illustrations and notes)
      - "Penny-Blood and Thunder," undated, (illustrated) (Box 14)
      - "The Perfect Gentleman: Observations Selected and Arranged, with a Foreword by Charles G. Shaw," undated (Box 15)
      - "Profile: Lady of Leisure" (Maria Louisa), undated (Box 15)
      - "Quick Lunch," undated (Box 15)
      - "The Real Romanoff," undated (Box 15)
      - "The Reason Why" (incomplete, A-C), undated (Box 15)
      - "The Reason Why" (incomplete, A-M), undated, (3 folders) (Box 15)
      - "Rhymed Recipes," undated, (illustrated) (Box 15)
      - "Rubber Neck," undated (Box 15)
      - "The Rubber Neck Wagon," undated (Box 15)
      - "She Loves Me; She Loves Me Not," undated (Box 15)
      - "Things I Have Always Liked," undated (Box 15)
      - Travel Writings (A-Z by title), undated (Box 15)
      - "The Uncommon Man: Observations Selected and Arranged, with a Foreword by Charles G. Shaw," undated (Box 15)
      - "The What Am I? Book," undated, (illustrated; parts 1-3 and 5-8) (Box 15)
      - "A Word or Two on Art," undated (Box 15)
      - "Yesterday's Tabloids," undated (Box 15)
    - Notebooks, 1923-1963, 3.1.5:
      Notes for Fiction include Volume 3, Notes for a Novel, 1920s; Volume 4, "A Notebook," No. 1, circa 1926; Volume 5, "A Notebook," No. 2, 1926-1927; Volume 6, "A Notebook," 1930-1931; and Volume 7, "Note Book," 1931.
      Travel Notebooks include Volume 8, Austria; Volume 9, "Notes on Berlin," undated; Volume 10, "London," (including notes on Paris), 1929-1930; Volume 12, "London Notes: Restaurants and Nightclubs," 1930; Volume 13, "Notes on London," 1931; Volume 14, London Restaurants; Volume 15, London; Volume 16, Paris; and Volume 17, Rome.
      - Volumes 1 and 2: Lists of Earnings and Stories, 1923, 1925 (Box 15)
      - Notes for Fiction, (2 folders) (Box 15)
      - Travel, Volumes 8-9, 1930, undated (Box 15)
      - Travel, Volume 10, 1929-1930 (Box 15)
      - Travel, Volumes 12-13, 1930, 1931 (Box 16)
      - Travel, Volumes 14-17, undated (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, Volume 18, 1936-1961 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, Volume 19, 1963 (Box 16)
    - Notes, 1939-1971, 3.1.6:
      - Addresses, undated, (2 volumes) (Box 16)
      - Children's Book Idea, undated, (illustrated) (Box 16)
      - First Aid Course Notes, undated (Box 16)
      - Illustration Ideas, undated (Box 16)
      - Lists of Owners of Paintings by Shaw, undated (Box 16)
      - Lists of Poems Accepted for Publication, 1958-1971, undated (Box 16)
      - Mailing Lists, 1939-1967, undated (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous, 1950-1959, undated (Box 16)
      - Plot and Story Ideas, undated (Box 16)
      - Price Lists (Shaw Paintings), 1949-1969, undated (Box 16)
      - Sketch Ideas, undated (Box 16)
      - Tinsel Print Information for Addison Gallery Exhibition, 1947 (Box 16)
      - Tobacco Figures, undated (Box 16)
      - "Tricks of the Trade," undated (Box 16)
      - Word and Phrase Origins, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16)
    - Plays, circa 1920s-circa 1960s, 3.1.7:
      - "The American Scene" (parts 1 and 2), undated (Box 16)
      - "High and Dry" (act 2), undated (Box 16)
      - "Rouge et Noir" (various versions of a one-act play), undated (Box 16)
      - Sketches and One-Act Plays, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - "Use Your Brain," undated (Box 16)
    - Poems, circa 1920s-1971, 3.1.8:
      - "About Me" – "Haiku," undated, (28 folders) (Box 17)
      - "Hail and Farewell" – "Poem for a Yesterday-Tomorrow," undated, (21 folders) (Box 18)
      - "Poem for the Day After Tomorrow" – "Zen;" Untitled, undated, (23 folders) (Box 19)
      - Poems, 1963-1971, (9 volumes in 5 folders) (Box 20)
    - Quizzes, circa 1920s-circa 1960s, 3.1.9:
      - "The All-American Know-Your-Country Quiz," undated (Box 20)
      - "The All American National Game Quiz," 1940 (Box 20)
      - "The All-American Quiz," undated (Box 20)
      - "Are You a New Yorker?," undated (Box 20)
      - "A Central Park Questionnaire," undated (Box 20)
      - "Comic Strip Quiz," undated (Box 20)
      - "Guess Again," undated (Box 20)
      - "A 'Last Word' Questionnaire," undated (Box 20)
      - "A 'Man's' Questionnaire," undated (Box 20)
      - "Movie Quiz," undated (Box 20)
      - "Name That Place," undated (Box 20)
      - "The New York Quiz Book," undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
      - "Popular Song Quiz," undated (Box 20)
      - "Quizzo," nos. 1-3, undated (Box 20)
      - "What's the Date?," undated (Box 20)
    - Short Writings, circa 1920s-circa 1960s, 3.1.10:
      - A-Z (by title) and Untitled, undated, (8 folders) (Box 20)
      - "The Important Book" (illustrated), undated, (see also: Box 13) (Box 46 (sol))
  - Writings by Other Authors, 1911-circa 1969, 3.2:
    Writings by other authors on a variety of topics include a children's book illustrated by Shaw, a review of Shaw's poetry, and an article about Shaw as a modern painter.
    - Brown, Margaret Wise. "Black and White" (illustrated by Shaw), 1944, (see: Box 46) (Box 20)
    - Brown, Margaret Wise. "The Sleeping Indians," undated (Box 20)
    - Collins, Patrick. "A Shaw of Another Color," undated (Box 20)
    - Fletcher, Richard. "Blind Alley: A Play in Three Acts," undated (Box 20)
    - Graham, John D. "Child-Hood (Child Within)" (incomplete), undated (Box 20)
    - Holty, Carl. Untitled (article about Shaw as a modern painter), undated (Box 20)
    - Romano, Liboria. Review of Time Has No Edge by Charles Shaw, 1966 (Box 20)
    - Shaw, Frank D. "Cincinnati in the Sixties," 1911 (Box 20)
    - Weaver, Clarence L. "Two Cinquains," circa 1969 (Box 20)
    - Webb, Rozana. "Charles Shaw……Poet Extraordinary," undated (Box 20)
    - Wilde, Oscar. "The Selfish Giant" (radio version), undated (Box 20)
    - Unknown. "Charles (with apologies to C. S.)", undated (Box 20)
    - Various Authors, Quotations, undated (Box 20)
    - Brown, Margaret Wise. "Black and White" (illustrated by Shaw), 1944, (see also Box 20) (Box 46 (sol))
- Artwork, 1929-1974, Series 4:; (Boxes 21-30; 47-49, OV 51; 10.15 linear ft.)
  This series is organized into 2 subseries:
  4.1: Artwork By Shaw, 1929-1974
  4.2: Artwork By Other Artists, 1941-circa 1956
  - Artwork by Shaw, 1929-1974, 4.1:
    Artwork by Shaw consists mainly of sketchbooks (340 volumes) that contain sketches and finished drawings in pencil and ink, watercolor and gouache paintings, pastels, and collages. Most volumes include notes on color, and many also contain poems, drafts of letters, and notes on miscellaneous topics. In addition, there are loose drawings in charcoal, pencil, and ink, as well as paintings in gouache and watercolor, and a small number of collages including a few photo collages. Shaw's writings (Series 3) include a number of manuscripts illustrated with drawings and gouache paintings.
    - Collages, 1940s, undated, (see also: Box 48; 3 folders) (Box 21)
    - Collages ("Eye Poems," photocopies), undated (Box 21)
    - Drawings (Box 21)
      - Charcoal, undated (Box 21)
      - Color Pencil, 1930s, undated, (2 folders; see also Box 49) (Box 21)
      - Ink, undated (Box 21)
      - Ink Portraits, 1940, undated, (see Box 49) (Box 21)
      - Pastel, undated, (see OV 51) (Box 21)
      - Pencil, 1930s-1950, undated, (see also Box 49; 6 folders) (Box 21)
      - Pencil Portraits and Figures, undated, (see Box 49) (Box 21)
    - Paintings (Box 21)
      - Gouache, 1940-1967, undated, (3 folders) (Box 21)
      - Gouache, 1951-1952, undated, (see Box 49) (Box 21)
      - Watercolor, 1943-1944, undated, (2 folders) (Box 21)
      - Watercolor, 1946, (see Box 49) (Box 21)
    - Rug Designs, 1939 (Box 21)
    - Sketchbooks (Box 21)
      - Volumes 1-5, 1929, 1930, 1932, 1935, (2 folders) (Box 21)
      - Volumes 6-16, 1935-1943, (see: Box 47) (Box 21)
      - Volumes 17-26, 1944-1948, 1955, (4 folders) (Box 21)
      - Volumes 27-61, 1955-1957, 1959-1964, (17 folders) (Box 22)
      - Volumes 62-97, 1964-1965, (18 folders) (Box 23)
      - Volumes 98-135, 1965-1966, (19 folders) (Box 24)
      - Volumes 136-171, 1966-1967, (18 folders) (Box 25)
      - Volumes 172-209, 1967-1969, (19 folders) (Box 26)
      - Volumes 210-241, July-August 1969-1973, (16 folders) (Box 27)
      - Volumes 242-284, circa 1973-1974, undated, (17 folders) (Box 28)
      - Volumes 285-318, undated, (17 folders) (Box 29)
      - Volumes 319-340, undated, (11 folders) (Box 30)
      - Volumes 6-16, 1953-1936, 1940-1942, (4 folders; see also Box 21) (Box 47 (sol))
      - Volumes 334-340, undated, (3 folders) (Box 48 (sol))
      - Volumes 341-343, undated, (2 folders) (Box 49 (sol))
    - Oversized Collages, undated, (see also Box 21) (Box 49 (sol))
    - Oversized Drawings, Color Pencil, undated, (see also Box 21) (Box 49 (sol))
    - Oversized Drawings, Ink (portraits), 1940, undated, (see also Box 21) (Box 49 (sol))
    - Oversized Drawings, Pencil, 1941-1943, undated, (see also Box 21) (Box 49 (sol))
    - Oversized Drawings, Pencil Portraits and Figures, undated, (see also Box 21) (Box 49 (sol))
    - Oversized Paintings, Gouache, 1951-1952, undated, (see also Box 21) (Box 49 (sol))
    - Oversized Paintings, Watercolor, 1946, (see also Box 21) (Box 49 (sol))
    - Drawings, Pastel, undated, (see also Box 21) (Box OV 51)
  - Artwork by Other Artists, 1941-circa 1956, 4.2:
    - Drawing, Charcoal Portrait probably of Shaw by Betty George, undated (Box 30)
    - Paintings, Watercolors by G. G. Drayton and M.A.L.; Gouache by Frances Brooks, 1941, undated (Box 30)
    - Prints, Woodcuts by Stell and Shevis, circa 1956 (Box 30)
- Financial Records, 1933-1971, Series 5:; (Boxes 30-31; 0.65 linear ft.)
  Financial records consist primarily of banking records, tax returns, and royalty statements. Records of art sales document sales for Shaw and other artists. Art-related receipts document activities such as shipping and framing.
  In addition to the financial records found in this series, a few records concerning the investments of Shaw's father, Charles Green Shaw, Jr., can be found in the family documents of Series 1: Biographical Information.
  Records are arranged alphabetically by subject and chronologically within folders.
  - Art Sales, 1935-1972 (Box 30)
  - Banking (Box 30)
    - Account Statements, 1944-1972 (Box 30)
    - Cancelled Checks, 1944-1971 (Box 30)
    - Passbook, 1918 (Box 30)
  - Contracts with Publishers, 1944-1966 (Box 31)
  - Insurance, 1947-1956 (Box 31)
  - Investments, 1916-1972, undated (Box 31)
  - Lease and Rent Control Documents, 1948-1970 (Box 31)
  - Payment for Writings, 1922-1957, undated (Box 31)
  - Receipts (Box 31)
    - Art-Related, 1946-1960, undated (Box 31)
    - Books Sold and Consigned, 1954-1970, undated (Box 31)
    - Tobacco Collection Purchases, 1930-1938 (Box 31)
    - Routine Expenses, 1912-1971, undated (Box 31)
  - Royalty Statements (Box 31)
    - Bell Syndicate; Brentano's; Country Poet; Farrar & Reinhart, 1927-1954 (Box 31)
    - Harper & Brothers/Harper & Row, 1944-1971, (2 folders) (Box 31)
    - Henry Hudson; John Day; Macaulay Co., 1928-1934 (Box 31)
    - William R. Scott, Inc./Young Scott Books, 1940-1958, undated (Box 31)
  - Social Security, 1970 (Box 31)
  - Taxes, 1933-1970 (Box 31)
- Scrapbooks, 1922-1970, Series 6:; (Boxes 31-34; 3.2 linear ft.)
  A total of 37 volumes document Shaw's art career and exhibitions, published writings, published poems, and miscellaneous subjects. Published writings primarily comprise prose with a few poems. Records relating to miscellaneous subjects document publicity for New York - Oddly Enough, published by Shaw in 1938, through correspondence and reviews and also include notes and clippings related to "The Question Is," a New York Sun column written by Shaw. Other subjects are documented in notes, clippings and printed material.
  Scrapbooks are arranged alphabetically by subject and chronologically thereafter.
  - Exhibitions, Volumes 1-5, 1935-1969, (volume 1 disbound) (Box 31)
  - Published Writings, Volumes 6-14, 1922-1931, undated (Box 32)
  - Published Poems, Volumes 15-28, 1954-1967 (Box 33)
  - Published Poems, Volumes 29-34, 1967-1970 (Box 34)
  - Miscellaneous Subjects (Box 34)
    - Volume 35, Post Card Album, undated, (disbound volume) (Box 34)
    - Volume 36, New York – Oddly Enough, 1938, (disbound volume) (Box 34)
    - Volume 37, "The Question Is," 1939, (disbound volume) (Box 34)
    - Volume 38, London, 1938, undated (Box 34)
    - Volume 39, New York, 1937, undated (Box 34)
- Printed Material, 1686-1979, Series 7:; (Boxes 34-41, 46; 7.6 linear ft.)
  Printed material by Shaw consists of articles, books written or illustrated by him, plays, and poems. Items by other authors are books, exhibition catalogs, plays, periodicals, and poems. Among the miscellaneous printed material are auction and book catalogs, clippings, and ephemera. Also included are a wide assortment of menus, along with theatrical memorabilia, travel brochures and printed souvenirs collected by Shaw.
  Additional printed material can be found in Series 6: Scrapbooks.
  This series is organized into 3 subseries. Material is arranged alphabetically by subject and chronologically within folders.
  7.1: Printed Material By Shaw, 1917-1972
  7.2: Printed Material By Other Authors, 1895-1979
  7.3: Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1686-1969
  - Printed Material By Shaw, 1917-1972, 7.1:
    - Articles (Box 34)
      - The Chronicle (Charles G. Shaw, Associate Editor; includes signed and unsigned articles by Shaw), 1917 (Box 34)
      - Miscellaneous Articles, 1928-1953, undated (Box 34)
    - Books by and/or Illustrated by Shaw (Box 34)
      - The Blue Guess Book: A Young Riddle Book in Pictures by Charles G. Shaw, circa 1942 (Box 34)
      - Dark Is Dark by John G. McCullough, pictures by Charles G. Shaw; The Giant of Central Park by Charles G. Shaw, 1947, 1940 (Box 34)
      - Heart in a Hurricane by Charles G. Shaw, illustrated by Ralph Barton, 1927 (Box 34)
      - It Looked Like Spilt Milk by Charles G. Shaw; Joy Parade by Charles G. Shaw, 1947, undated, (see reel 75: 846-862) (Box 35)
      - Pitter Patter by Dorothy W. Baruch with illustrations by Charles G. Shaw; This Is the Milk That Jack Drank adapted from Mother Goose by William R. Scott with paintings by Charles G. Shaw (dust jacket only), 1943, undated (Box 35)
    - Clippings (Box 35)
      - Letters to the Editor, undated (Box 35)
      - Newspaper Columns ("How Well Do You Know New York?"), 1939, undated (Box 35)
    - Plays (Box 35)
      - "The Bus" in Experimental Theater One Anthology, 1959 (Box 35)
      - Galley Sheets ("The Bus" and "Told By Moonlight"), undated (Box 35)
    - Poems, (see also Series 6: Scrapbooks) (Box 35)
      - Anthologies with Poems by Shaw, 1957-1972, undated, (4 folders) (Box 35)
      - Galley Sheets and Clippings, 1955-1971, undated (Box 35)
      - Poetry Collections by Shaw (Box 35)
        - Into the Light, 1959 (Box 35)
        - Into the Now, 1969 (Box 35)
        - Time Has No Edge, 1966 (Box 35)
      - Poetry Collections with Poems by Shaw, 1958-1968 (Box 35)
      - Poetry Magazines with Poems by Shaw, 1948-1960, (5 folders) (Box 35)
      - Poetry Magazines with Poems by Shaw, 1961-1966, (15 folders) (Box 36)
      - Poetry Magazines with Poems by Shaw, 1966-1970, (16 folders) (Box 37)
      - Poetry Magazines with Poems by Shaw, 1970-1972, undated, (8 folders) (Box 38)
  - Printed Material By Other Authors, 1895-1979, 7.2:
    - About/Mentioning Shaw, or containing Reproductions (Box 38)
      - Biographical Information, 1914-1974, undated (Box 38)
      - Book Catalogs and Order Forms, 1943, 1966, undated (Box 38)
      - Book, American Abstract Artists by Ruth Gurin, 1936-1966 (Box 38)
      - Catalogs of Collections Containing Artwork by Shaw, 1957-1959, undated (Box 38)
      - Clippings, 1927-1962, undated (Box 38)
      - Exhibition Information re: Shaw Collection of Tinsel Prints at Addison Gallery, 1947 (Box 38)
      - Gallery Advertisements, 1946, 1951, undated (Box 38)
      - Reviews of Books, 1928-1966, undated (Box 38)
      - Reviews of Exhibitions, 1937-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 38)
      - Review of Play, 1920 (Box 38)
      - Theater Program, undated (Box 38)
    - Books (Box 38)
      - Artists Equity Association and the Woodstock Artists Association. The Artist and the Museum, 1950 (Box 38)
      - Cooper, Douglas. Paul Klee; Daniell, A. E. London Riverside Churches, 1953, 1897 (Box 38)
      - Forge, Andrew. Klee (Second Volume); Gallatin, A. E. Of Art: Plato to Picasso, 1954, 1944 (Box 38)
      - Graham, John D. System and Dialectics of Art (with letter, lengthy inscription, and corrections), 1937 (Box 38)
      - Haskin, Frederic J. Everybody's Coin Book; Hauf and Billy. Paris vieux et neuf, 1939, undated (Box 38)
      - Jones, Sydney R. Les habitations villageoisse en angleterre, 1912 (Box 39)
      - Kassák, Ludwig and László Maholy Nagy. Buch Neuer Künstler, 1922 (Box 39)
      - Muller, Joseph-Emile. Klee Magic Squares; Richards, H. S. Horse Brasses (Figure Subjects), 1957, undated (Box 39)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, Invitations, and Announcements (Box 39)
      - Charles G. Shaw, 1935-1979, undated, (7 folders) (Box 39)
      - Charles G. Shaw, 1945-1966, undated, (see also reel 75: frames 817-845) (Box 39)
      - Other Artists, 1930-1969, undated, (8 folders) (Box 39)
    - Periodicals (see also: 7.1 - Poetry Magazines) (Box 39)
      - Periodicals, A (Abstraction creation art non figurative; ARTnews; Axis), 1935-1936, 1972 (Box 39)
      - Periodicals, C (Cahiers d'art; Connoisseur; Critique), 1933, 1944, 1946 (Box 39)
      - Periodicals, F (Flair; Formes; France Illustration), 1930-1931, 1946-1950, (see also: Box 46) (Box 40)
      - Periodicals, G-H (Gallery Guide; Havana), 1929, 1966 (Box 40)
      - Periodicals, M-N (Magazine Antiques; Magazine of Art; Main Currents in Modern Thought; Manuscript Market; Messenger; M.K.R.'s Art Outlook; New York Art Calendar; News From Home), 1898, 1935-1966, undated, (4 folders) (Box 40)
      - Periodicals, P (Partisan Review; Plastique), 1937-1939 (Box 40)
      - Periodicals, S-V (Sketch; Trace; View), 1895, 1944, 1965 (Box 40)
    - Play, Suter, William. "Quiet Family: An Original Farce" (with notes and clippings about various productions with Charles G. Shaw, Jr., father, in cast), 1870s (Box 40)
    - Poems (Box 40)
      - Mason, Jordan Mason. A Legionere (Charles G. Shaw a patron), undated (Box 40)
      - Poetry Magazines (no Shaw poems), 1955-1972, (6 folders) (Box 40)
    - Periodicals, France Illustration, 1946, (see also Box 40) (Box 46 (sol))
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1686-1969, 7.3:
    - Auction Catalogs, 1934-1967, undated, (4 folders) (Box 40)
    - Book Advertisements and Prospectuses, 1964, undated (Box 40)
    - Book Catalogs, 1930-1960, undated, (3 folders) (Box 41)
    - Catalogs, Miscellaneous Merchandise, undated (Box 41)
    - Clippings, Art Subjects, 1938-1940, undated (Box 41)
    - Clippings, Miscellaneous Subjects, 1918-1938, undated (Box 41)
    - Club Rosters and Membership Lists, 1924-1948 (Box 41)
    - Ephemera, 1686-1969, undated, (see also: Box 46) (Box 41)
    - Menus (Box 41)
      - France, 1929-1932, undated, (see also: Box 46) (Box 41)
      - London, 1920-1932, undated, (see also: Box 46) (Box 41)
      - New York, 1920-1931, undated, (see also: Box 46) (Box 41)
      - Shipboard, 1929, undated (Box 41)
    - Museum Publications, 1931-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - Programs (Box 41)
      - Concerts, undated (Box 41)
      - Miscellaneous Events, 1912-1959, undated (Box 41)
      - Theater, 1922-1948, undated, (3 folders) (Box 41)
    - Reproductions (Box 41)
      - Charles G. Shaw, undated (Box 41)
      - Other Artists, 1800s-1900s, (2 folders) (Box 41)
    - Theatrical Memorabilia (see also: Programs, Theater) (Box 41)
      - Broadsides, 1784-1838 (Box 41)
      - Interior and Exterior Views of Theaters; Ticket, 1794-1830, undated (Box 41)
    - Travel Brochures and Printed Souvenirs (Box 41)
      - Boston, 1900 (Box 41)
      - England, undated (Box 41)
      - France, 1930-1937, undated (Box 41)
      - Germany; New Orleans, undated (Box 41)
      - New York, undated (Box 41)
      - Vienna, undated (Box 41)
    - Ephemera, 1940, (see also Box 41) (Box 46 (sol))
    - Menus (Box 46 (sol))
      - France, 1930-1932, (see also Box 41) (Box 46 (sol))
      - London, 1930-1931, undated, (see also Box 41) (Box 46 (sol))
      - New York, 1930-1934, (see also Box 41) (Box 46 (sol))